Before we jump into our demonstrations and we start walking through our specific scenarios,
let's take an opportunity just to introduce you to the
company that we'll be using throughout this entire course.
And so they're a financial services company named HCL,
and they really focus on large to enterprise customers,
although they do some have small and medium size business
customers in there as well. The size of the deals,
they really do loans and loan generation as well as some financing
options both for new construction as well as existing construction,
as well as they do some lease referral information as well. And depending on the size of the deal,
it really varies depending upon the specific product services that they're looking at, and sometimes that
can be affected by some of the different loan origination dates and items that they're working with.
They do have a lot of customers who are very heavy on social media, and we'll talk a
little bit more about the social media aspect of it when we get into another module,
but they do have a very proven sales methodology that really isn't being followed by their employees.
And so what they've noticed over the last year or so is that they've
really started to lose a lot more deals than they normally do,
and they've been able to really trace that back to not
following the proven sales methodology that they have.
So they want to come up with a better way to be able to enforce
that functionality and be able to work with it from there.
And they also have their leads coming in from many different scenarios. It could be customers coming
in to trade shows and sales or relationship executives entering that information into the system.
It could be leads coming in from websites that they're looking
at. It could just be items coming into the application.
But they want to provide multiple ways for leads to come into the system. And then they
also understand that many of their users spend a lot of their time in other applications,
it might be Outlook, might be Word, might be Excel, and they want to be
sure that they're able to leverage some of those existing technologies,
particularly from an Outlook perspective, to be able to effectively enter
information into the application without having to do a lot of back and forth.
And so that's really the company that we're going to look at in this particular module, and the
remaining items are really going to identify how Dynamics 365 for Sales can really help provide
each one of those individual situations and meet those needs that they're looking for.