&gt;&gt; Everybody, as the top of the hour,
we're going to give people another couple of
minutes to join from other mediums
so we'll get started in two minutes.
All right, folks. We're going to give it about one
more minute before we get started.
All right, everybody.
It's a couple of minutes after the hour,
we're going to go ahead and get started as people join.
Welcome to the May 2018 Skype
for Business and Microsoft Teams Readiness Brown Bag.
My name is Tim Ballew,
and I am the Business Program Manager
for CSS Learning for these products,
and I'm joined today by members of our Readiness Team:
our learning development managers
and instructional designers.
During today's session, we'll be
reviewing the May feature releases and updates for
Skype for Business and Teams' product family
and we'll be providing
you some additional resources
for more information on those items.
We anticipate that today's session
will be roughly 50 minutes,
we won't necessarily take the whole hour this time.
And please note that
a recording will be made available as
a training and success factors after the session is over.
So, a real quick reminder
about our confidentiality obligations.
We do not disclose confidential information,
and this information that we're sharing today has not
necessarily been reviewed for public consumption.
So, be aware.
Today we're going to be looking at
typical topics of Lync and Skype for Business Server.
We'll be talking about Skype
for Business Online Calling Plans,
Direct Routing and Coexistence Modes.
Our Phones and Devices section will
cover Skype Room Systems updates,
and they will cover all of the clients.
We'll talk a little bit about the network assessment tool
and then review current recently released trainings,
they have the upcoming trainings to look out for.
So, with that I'm going to go
ahead and hand it over to Darren Hansen,
who is going to walk us through
our features and fixes. Darren!
&gt;&gt; All right thank you much Tim.
All right, so we're going to start off
today with an update
for Skype for Business Server 2015.
This is highly anticipated CU for CU7.
It is going to come out here in June in a little bit.
We don't have an exact date but it should be
coming up in the next few weeks.
So, there are a lot of
fixes and improvements and
stuff like that that have gone into this update.
We're going to highlight a few here on the slides,
and then the majority of them are in the appendix,
which is linked right down here.
So, the first one that we're going to talk
about is an issue where we now
support anonymous PSTN callers starting
a static meeting without
an authenticated user in Skype for Business.
Another one where we support
the end meeting functionality for
Skype for Business on Mac in 2015,
enabling Skype meetings app to replace
the Skype for Business Web app and
Skype for Business Server 2015.
Then Microsoft SQL servers
2016 is available for the back end server.
Oh! I'm sorry, Thank you Colin.
I did not take over as presenter there.
All right so now you should be seeing
the Skype for Business Server 2015
slides with a few improvements here on the screen.
So, we get to the last one there were
Microsoft SQL server 2016 is available
for backend servers of Skype for Business Server 2015.
So, we now support that.
And again, there are probably
20 or more additional fixes and improvements
in the appendix there so make sure you download the deck
from the meeting attachments and take a look there.
So, now moving off of
server and onto sort of Skype for Business online,
you can see that all of these things have to do
with Microsoft Teams but they also do
reflect functionality and Skype for Business
online too for customers who are
using for example calling plans,
Direct Routing and coexistence modes apply.
But, as we move forward
you'll also see in the top right hand corner
that there are some logos for Teams and Skype.
Those just help you know which
one we're talking about on each
individual slide as we go through the deck,
you see we've made some updates to the template.
So, we're just trying to
make that a little bit more clear.
So, Microsoft Teams and
Skype for Business Online calling plans in
Canada are now general available,
that was updated or released on May first.
So, all calls between US and Canada users in
both directions are now considered
domestic and not international so that's a big win.
Calling plans work with both teams
as well as Skype for Business and you can buy
today in Office 365 together obviously,
they make calling enabled for
your organization using your primary phone number.
So, make sure your customers know about that.
There is information in the blog here.
Direct Routing, if you
haven't heard about Direct Routing before.
It's essentially CCE or Cloud.
There are definitely two different things
but this is basically using
your on premise infrastructure with Teams to route calls.
So, this was released on May 15.
Customers can choose to sign up for preview
and they will get support through our in market teams.
It is a preview release,
so just be aware of that.
What if you do get a call and you
need assistance with answering direct routing calls?
You can post your question here,
which leads to the real one note I believe,
and SME will respond or you
can reach out to one of these SMEs listed.
So, I know that there are some of you on the phone,
who are on this list so,
I hope you don't get too many calls or questions.
There's also plenty of
information in our training that we just released,
as well as the UC real one note documents.
So, Carolyn and other SMEs did a
really bang up job in documenting Direct Routing,
documenting troubleshooting methodologies,
scenarios, all sorts of stuff.
So, it's very well understood product
at this point and we're just entering previews.
So, coexistence mode, you may have also heard about this.
Greg talked about it in our last brown bag last month,
when he demo the modern portal
and the modes for upgrading.
So, the modern portal now removes the interrupt policy
and upgrade policy as
two separate entities and gives us coexistence modes.
The goal is to consolidate
the upgrade experience when
transitioning from Skype for Business to Teams,
because it's pretty confusing as it is today.
There are some customers and TAP,
who have already set the Teams interrupt policy before,
and those customers are flighted
for the Team's only upgrade coexistence mode.
So, they're the only customers right now who can
fully switch the Teams
and have Skype for Business disabled.
The rest of the customers are given
the option of I believe,
Skype for Business only or Teams club,
and so make sure to check out the appendix.
There are some screenshots in there to understand what
the coexistence mode looks like
and how to set it, as well as a blog.
So, make sure you go check those out.
We also will be releasing
training here in the next few weeks
on the upgrade story and the interrupt mode story,
so make sure to look out for that.
So, that does it
for Skype for Business Online
specifically or Microsoft Teams.
So, now we'll move on to Phone Devices,
where we've got some updates
or information on Skype Room Systems.
So, this one is a performance issue on
Skype Room Systems v2 devices
that are on Surface Pro 2017 based devices.
So there is a performance issues when you join
a meeting with a combination
of HDMI, wired ingest sharing.
So, you're plugging the HDMI into your laptop,
and sharing through the Skype Room System.
When you have dual front-of-room displays,
and multiple remote video streams being used.
So, when all of those things are
happening in conjunction in one meeting,
you might get some performance issues.
So, possible workarounds are desktop sharing into
the meeting via Skype for Business Application
instead of the HDMI cable,
or reducing the front-off-room display configuration
to a single screen.
So, that's just be aware of that if you're
using all of these features
of Skype Room Systems at one time,
you might get some performance issues,
specifically on the Surface Pro 2017 based devices.
So, this is just to let you know that documentation
has been updated for Skype Room Systems v2.
It improves the onscreen keyboard behavior,
or just lets you know about
the onscreen keyboard behavior
in version 1709 of Windows 10,
and improvements to prepare
for updates to future operating systems.
All right. Moving on to Lync,
and Skype for Business desktop,
and mobile clients, we also have Teams in here as well.
So, we will start off with Skype for Business 2015.
This was an update released back on May 1st.
Just one issue fixed here with a location display issue
if using E911 is set to true in Skype for Business.
So there, the downloads available there,
as well as the KB if you'd like more information.
Joe correctly called out
that this should be May 1st, 2018 not 2013.
So, thank you.
Skype for Business 2016,
also released on May 1st.
I know that the same fix for
the 2015 client is also in the 2016 quite right here,
in addition to two other ones.
So, unread messages of a reopened chatroom are
incorrectly indicated when restarting
Skype for Business 2016,
so that issue is fixed.
Another issue fixed where you
were repeatedly added as a delegate.
You would receive that message every time you log in
to Skype for Business 2015 even if you were,
had already been a member of that,
or even selected as a delegate for that user.
So, make sure to check out the download links,
as well as KB.
So, Microsoft Teams.
Some of this is available
publicly in your regular Team's client.
You can go to the, I believe, the T bot,
and look at what's new in Teams.
So, just some new features,
and new improvements that they've made.
I believe this was last months
that we may have already covered it.
So, you can now send messages from the command box.
For the contact card,
you can dial out or into a group call,
auto import, or auto favorite import channels.
That means that an admin of a channel,
or an owner of a channel,
or a group can automatically
favorites certain channels for
you when you join the team.
New views in the Microsoft Planner tab.
I believe there's graph views,
and different schedule views,
you can look at the schedule all up.
Then, in the charts view of the Planner tab,
you can stay up to date on
the status of your plans obviously.
So, there's also filtering options where you can
group tasks by buckets such as a sign to,
progress, due dates, and labels.
So, you have a lot more way to look at your project data.
You can now use the SharePoint tab
to place important pages,
news articles, and list as individual tabs in a channel.
So, instead of just having a link to one SharePoint page,
you can add a list to specific SharePoint pages,
and have that show up in your team channel.
&gt;&gt; Hey, Darren we got a quick question regarding the
delegate data fix for 2016 MSI.
Does that now imply that it supports 25 delegators.
&gt;&gt; I didn't get that implication from what I read.
I think we'd have to check the KB for more information,
but I wouldn't know off the top of my head.
So, that's a good question that if it's not in the KB,
we can go ahead, and take a look at that.
So, Tim, if you might take a note to follow up on that.
We can check later.
&gt;&gt; I will do that.
&gt;&gt; Thank you. All right.
So, moving on more on Microsoft Teams,
few highlights on the iOS, and Android apps.
We now have better meeting capabilities on the apps.
You can request a call to your Teams
phone to connect you to a meeting instead of dialing in.
That's very similar to Skype for Business,
and how it's done today.
So, you can easily turn a one on
one call into a group call,
or transfer one on one call
to someone else, or forward calls.
This is all in the mobile app, remember.
So, some of the stuff is already
available on the desktop app,
now it's in mobile.
So, you can now create Teams for mobile, and Teams EDU.
So, specifically you have to be a EDU customer,
using classrooms, and teachers,
and students can now create,
edit, and delete teams on mobile.
So, as we announced this last week, or last month,
but more about the Windows Phone apps for Teams,
the app for Teams,
and Skype for Business is being retired.
So, after this takes effects,
users would no longer be able to
download the app from the Store,
and the app will no longer be supported.
So, we'll continue to invest in the iOS,
and Android apps on desktop,
and Windows, but no longer the Windows Phone apps.
This is essentially the same thing
what I just highlighted.
This takes effect July 20th.
So, beginning July 20th,
the app will no longer be in the Store.
However, existing users will still be
able to use the app until October 20th.
At which point, the Teams app will no longer work,
and users will see an
error message when they try to connect.
So, it's just recommended that if you want
to continue using it until October 20th,
go ahead, and install it before
July 20th when it disappears from the App Store.
So, additional information, there's a blog there.
Moving on to Skype for Business for Mac,
we have a few fixes that went into this release,
that was came out May 8th.
So, an issue where excessive CPU usage was
happening when opening a new conversation
while offline has been fixed.
Another issue that prevented
notifications of new phone calls from
being visible when
a Skype for Business window was zoomed,
has been fixed, changed
how the IM disclaimer messages are displayed.
Fixed a crash in
some cases where users tries to sign out,
and an issue that prevented a call window from displaying
properly when trying to leave a voicemail for a contact.
So, there is some additional information
in the blog post here.
So, Skype for Business on Windows Phone,
this is essentially what we just talked about.
Skype for Business on Windows Phone
8.1 will no longer be available for
download beginning in December 2019.
Skype for Business on Windows 10 Mobile
will no longer be available for download.
So, that's still awaits in the future.
Yeah. Same thing with Teams
here just install the app before it
disappears off the Store.
That happens in August 2018.
So, August 2018 for Windows Phone 8.1,
it won't be available for download.
Then, all the way in December 2019
for Skype for Business on Windows 10 Mobile.
So, if your customers are still using Windows 10,
make sure they know about those dates so
they don't lose their-
Yeah, it is kind of
sad when his phone was a great little phone.
So, the Network Assessment Tool,
many of you may have used this or maybe aware of it.
You may even have heard the announcement,
but it's been updated
to also do Network Assessment for Microsoft Teams now.
So, even if a customer doesn't have
an Office 365 subscription yet,
you can still use this as a pre-sales stage to evaluate
whether their network is ready to support
all the various different features and
functionalities of Skype for Business,
whether they have enough bandwidth,
whether they can connect to the specific endpoints.
It does all this stuff.
So, you can get it very easily
by installing a PowerShell module and running
the Install-Module M365NetworkTestingTool commandement,
and then running Invoke-M365CreateShortcuts
and that will just create a shortcut on
your desktop and your Start Menu.
Then go ahead and launch it.
So, it is a very useful tool.
It goes over a lot of information.
And so, it's packaged up in a nice little UI,
so your customers will be happy when they see it.
So, yeah, that's been updated.
The request from the tool creators
is just to start using it.
Get it in front of customers,
figure out what they like,
what they don't like, provide feedback to the tool.
I believe there's definitely
team channels that a lot of you
are probably involved in where they've talked about this.
I believe there's feedback
within the tool that you can email.
So, what are their plans for the tool next?
They want to provide
each information icon that pops up when it does a test.
They want to link to
specific guidance on the fast track website.
Right now, the order of testing is swapped.
They test connectivity first and then audio quality.
The device parser is also updated to reflect
newer headsets and speakerphones which
have been certified by the call quality team.
The Desktop/Start Menu icons
are applied when the module is updated,
instead of each time the application launches.
Then the public web URL's and a blog will follow soon.
So, keep a look out for that.
There is some additional information right here.
And that does it for our releases,
and updates, and stuff like that.
So, I'll go ahead and head back to back to
Tim and he can take it from there.
&gt;&gt; Thanks so much, Darren. Great overview.
In terms of Special Topics and Training Releases,
we'll look at the short view backwards and forwards.
While I go ahead and share these slides,
I want to invite people to put the chat window
any request they have were
training on Skype for Business or Teams topics.
We have been very much focused on
capturing training on major feature releases in Teams,
but we also do strive to
provide training on the knowledge gap areas,
areas in which you're uncomfortable providing support.
So, as I talk about these slides,
I invite you to go ahead and toss
any suggestions you have in the chat window
about training topics you'd like to see
coverage to up skill,
where you feel like you need it.
So, Recently Release Training.
We're having a little bit of a problem, it looks like,
with the slide show in the proper content.
I'm going to go ahead and speak to this.
But I won't have a visual
to show you. Apologies for that.
We have released Microsoft Teams Direct Routing training,
as Darren alluded to,
but please give us feedback on that course.
This is going to give you
a good overview of
the direct routing value add capabilities.
It's going to help you
understand how direct routing is set up,
and with the new features are and
applying basic troubleshooting steps
for various scenarios,
and that includes known issues as well.
So, please do check out the Direct Routing training.
Prior to that, we issued our Cloud Recording Training,
an another recently released feature.
We also have Microsoft Teams
and Skype for Business interoperability course out there
that is being updated
as configuration options are changing.
So, please do also view that training.
Again, apologies for the lack
of content showing on screen.
So, coming up in June for Teams,
we are going to be addressing
the Skype for Business to Teams
Upgrade Process and Customer Experience.
The schedule for these upgrades is being finalized,
but we can look for this activity to kick
off and start small
but ramp up beginning in the next month or so.
We'll also be covering Call Delegation
and Consultative Transfer,
and we are watching
Teams Federation features lighting up,
and we will be training on those features
as we have more information
that would be useful to support agents.
So, beyond that, we'll be looking
to cover Teams Broadcast Meetings,
which will include a new feature called
Leadership Connection geared toward connecting
executive leadership and companies to their audience.
We are looking at consolidating PSTN Teams,
PSTN Calling Feature Releases
into a consolidated training as well.
Our June Brown Bag is going to be on the 26.
If you have an idea for a topic
or anything you want to hear about,
please do let us know with that email address.
We'll be happy to arrange.
Let me just point out
a couple items on the Blogs of Note.
We have that updated roadmap for
the Microsoft Teams Upgrade from Skype for
Business that will give a lot of
information on feature plans.
That's a good place to go for
comprehensive information on what
that activity looks like.
Like I said, we'll be addressing
that process in a training coming up.
You'll notice that we have
our planning direct routing link
included in this set of blogs,
which is an overview of how customers are
to approach and configure and set up
direct routing might be useful for you.
I will just also point out that GDPR has
been a big focus obviously in the last week or so.
There's a link here to the specific information about how
GDPR pertains to
Skype for Business Server and Lync Server.
And as always, we are
available through our Infopedia page where
you'll find our training catalog
and contact information for our team.
I'm taking a look at the feedback we're getting in
the chat window regarding
topics you'd like to see covered.
This is very useful information for us.
We're going to take these suggestions and see
if we can follow up with
a guest speaker or
provide you deeper information on next Brown Bag.
Thank you so much. And with that,
I want to thank Darren Hansen and the rest
of our CSS Learning and Readiness Team.
And of course, those of you who participated today.
Thank you so much and have a great day.